{"tossups": [{"question": "P. W. Anderson showed that, when the disorder potential is too strong, interference of a wavefunction with itself results in this type of material. Because of correlation effects, an example of these materials occurs when the on-site repulsion is much greater than the inter-site hopping, which are the two terms in the Hubbard model. In the simplest possible MOSFET (\"MOSS\"-fet), this type of material underlies the gate terminal. In general, these materials are characterized by a very high bandgap, o\u2884en over four electron volts. If these materials can be polarized by an electric field, as are often found in capacitors, they are called dielectrics. For 10 points, name these materials with tightly bound electrons in which current does not flow, as contrasted with conductors.", "answer": "electrical insulators [prompt on \"dielectrics\" before \"dielectrics\"]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>electrical insulators</u></b> [prompt on <u>dielectrics\"</u> before \"dielectrics]", "acceptable": ["electrical insulators"], "promptable": ["dielectrics\""], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One of these figures wears a fur hat in a painting depicting a fight over a pickled herring. The phrase \u201cno fire; will you have any tomorrow?\u201d appears on a stove around which several of these figures \u201cwarm themselves.\u201d In another painting, two of these figures form an equilateral triangle with a man wearing a sign that reads \u201ccivet\u201d (sih-VAY). One of these figures is depicted through a window in the distance under the letters S and O on a banner that reads \u201cvive le sociale.\u201d Two of them are shown with a mop and broom \u201cfighting for the body of a hanged man.\u201d One of these figures wears a black-and-green top hat at the bottom left of Christ\u2019s Entry into Brussels. James Ensor often painted, for 10 points, what figures that, in Pieter Bruegel\u2019s The Triumph of Death, attack the living with their bony limbs?", "answer": "skeletons [prompt on \"corpses\" or \"bodies\" or \"bones\" or \"dead people\" or similar answers]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>skeletons</u></b> [prompt on <u>corpses</u> or <u>bodies</u> or <u>bones</u> or <u>dead people</u> or <u>similar answers</u>]", "acceptable": ["skeletons"], "promptable": ["corpses", "bodies", "bones", "dead people", "similar answers"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Because it has a low isoelectric point, a protein that regulates this process by binding XIAP is named DIABLO. This process populates the top-right quadrant of a propidium iodide\u2013gated flow cytometry assay. A protein complex named for this process looks like a seven-spoked wheel. Proteins that regulate this process in C. elegans (\"see\" eh-leh-GANZ) are prefixed \"c-e-d.\" DNA extracted during this process runs like a ladder on a gel because it is fragmented. Trophic factors prevent this process; a protein that also prevents this process is upregulated in lymphoma, opposes Bax and Bad, and prevents cytochrome C from escaping the mitochondria. Cell membranes bleb, and caspases degrade proteins, during this process. DNA damage detected by p53 can trigger, for 10 points, what process of programmed cell death?", "answer": "apoptosis [prompt on \"(programmed) cell death\"]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>apoptosis</u></b> [prompt on <u>(programmed) cell death</u>]", "acceptable": ["apoptosis"], "promptable": ["(programmed) cell death"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "programmed"}, {"question": "A form of music from this country can proceed in \"colotomic\" rhythmic cycles for as long as 256 beats. In this country, the German painter Walter Spies (VAHL-tur SHPEEZ) developed a fast, rhythmic, a cappella chant called ketjak (KET-yahk). Novices o\u2884en perform a piece from this country called \"Golden Rain,\" or \"Udan Mas.\" Tempo \u2884exibility in this country's music is evoked in the \u2734rst movement of the piece Estampes (ess-TAHMP-uh). The scales pelog and slendro are used in music from this country, where ensembles o\u2884en accompany wayang shadow-puppet shows. An 1889 performance of an ensemble from this country partially inspired Claude Debussy's use of the whole-tone scale and his musical piece \"Pagodas.\" Gong-based ensemble music called gamelan is the traditional music of, for 10 points, what country's islands of Bali and Java?", "answer": "Indonesia [or Republic of Indonesia; or Republik Indonesia]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Indonesia</u></b> [or <b><u>Republic of Indonesia</u></b>; or <b><u>Republik Indonesia</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Indonesia", "Republic of Indonesia", "Republik Indonesia"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A text from this school of thought contains the story of a man who picks up a skull on the roadside, uses it as a pillow, and converses about death with it in his sleep. In another story from this school of thought, a man whose wife just died is found happily drumming on a bowl. The \"Inner Chapters\" are found in a text from this school of thought; another text from this tradition claims that the only important motion is \"returning\" and notes that a pot is useful because of its emptiness. This school of thought uses the metaphor of an uncarved wooden block to represent human nature. The concept of \"action through inaction,\" or \"wu wei\" (\"woo way\"), is central to, for 10 points, what Chinese school of thought based on the teachings of Zhuangzhi and Laozi (JWANG-zuh and \"LOUD\"-zuh), the latter of whom wrote the a book whose title translates as \"The Book of the Way of Virtue\"?", "answer": "Taoism [or Daoism; accept forms of the words Tao or Dao]", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "category": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Taoism</u></b> [or <b><u>Daoism</u></b>; accept <b><u>forms of the words Tao</u></b> or <b><u>Dao</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Taoism", "Daoism", "forms of the words Tao", "Dao"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A tradition of walking barefoot in the morning of this day stems from a line in a hymn stating \"on our dryness pour thy dew.\" In the Middle Ages, rose petals would sometimes be scattered on this holiday from holes in church ceilings, from which a dove would also descend. This holiday derives its scriptural basis from a scene in which a crowd of 3,000 people comes together a\u2884er a sermon about King David's prophecies. This holiday is based on a scene in the second chapter of the Acts of the Apostles in which Galilean, Parthian, Ephesian, Latin, and hundreds of other languages are spoken by worshipers who are \"\u2734lled with the Holy Spirit.\" The birth of the church is traditionally celebrated on, for 10 points, what holiday named for the fact that it falls on the 50th day a\u2884er Easter?", "answer": "Pentecost [accept Whitsunday]", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Pentecost</u></b> [accept <b><u>Whitsunday</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Pentecost", "Whitsunday"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character in this novel develops a philosophy \"trampl[ing] on the past\" and \"crush[ing] it\" a\u2884er returning from England. Father Huismans (wee-mahn), a Belgian priest at a lyce\u0301e (lee-SAY), teaches Ferdinand, who befriends this novel's protagonist while staying with Raymond and Yvette. A servant whose name, Metty, means \"someone of mixed race\" works for the protagonist of this novel, who takes a native lover named Zabeth. This novel's protagonist gets engaged to Nazruddin's daughter and becomes disillusioned at its end while nominally heading \"The Domain.\" Indar is a childhood friend of this novel's protagonist, a businessman named Salim. An African dictator named the \"Big Man\" appears in, for 10 points, what V. S. Naipaul novel titled for the geographic location of the central town?", "answer": "A Bend in the River", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>A Bend in the River</u></b>", "acceptable": ["A Bend in the River"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The multiplicity function gives the mass fraction in these structures in Press\u00c2\u2013Schechter theory. In linear tidal torque theory, angular momentum acquisition \u2734rst occurs in \"proto\" examples of these structures. In N-body simulations, the \"virial mass\" and \"concentration parameter\" determine the density pro\u2734les of these structures, as demonstrated by Navarro, Frenk, and White. These structures are o\u2884en de\u2734ned as having a density 200 times the critical density. In the standard model, galaxy formation originates from their \"dark matter\" type. Globular clusters and metal-poor stars mainly constitute the region of a spiral galaxy, surrounding the disk, that's denoted by this term. For 10 points, the \"galactic\" type of what structure is named in analogy to the faint and diffuse light around the head of a saint?", "answer": "halos [accept dark matter halos or galactic halos; accept overdensities or overdensity before \"200\"; prompt on \"galaxies\" or \"galaxy\" before \"galaxy\"]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>halos</u></b> [accept <b><u>dark matter halos</u></b> or <b><u>galactic halos</u></b>; accept <b><u>overdensities</u></b>accept <b><u>overdensity</u></b> before \"200; prompt on <u>galaxies</u>prompt on <u>galaxy\"</u> before \"galaxy]", "acceptable": ["halos", "dark matter halos", "galactic halos", "overdensities", "overdensity"], "promptable": ["galaxies", "galaxy\""], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A\u2884er the sinking of the Vyner Brooke, 21 members of this profession were massacred by Japanese troops on Bangka (bahng-kah) Island. A\u2884er being trained in this profession in England, Henny Tscherning (\"CHAIR\"-ning) brought modern pedagogical methods in this profession to Denmark. Traugott von Sauberzweig (\"TROW\"-got von ZOW-berts-vyge) was removed from his position as military governor of Brussels a\u2884er ordering the execution of one of these people named Edith Cavell. A group of these people called the Angels of Bataan continued to perform their duties as prisoners of war in the Philippines. A woman in this profession, who invented the \"polar area diagram\" to chart causes of mortality, worked at the Scutari barracks during the Crimean War. For 10 points, name this profession of \"The Lady with the Lamp,\" Florence Nightingale.", "answer": "nurses [accept nursing profession or answers such as army nurses or battle\u2734eld nurses; prompt on \"medics\" or similar answers; do not accept or prompt on \"doctors\" or similar answers]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>nurses</u></b> [accept <b><u>nursing profession</u></b> or <b><u>answers such as army nurses</u></b> or <b><u>battle\u2734eld nurses</u></b>; prompt on <u>medics</u> or <u>similar answers</u>; do not accept or prompt on \"doctors\" or \"similar answers\"]", "acceptable": ["nurses", "nursing profession", "answers such as army nurses", "battle\u2734eld nurses"], "promptable": ["medics", "similar answers"], "rejectable": ["doctors", "similar answers"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Completing the single-player mode of this game can result in a screen showing the player's character stuck inside a wooden frame with the message \"you are great,\" when the player uses the only character that has a unique shield. In single-player mode, this game includes \"bonus\" levels in which the player \"races to the \u2734nish,\" \"boards the platforms,\" and \"breaks the targets.\" Enemies in this game's single-player mode include a \"giant\" with three allies, a very heavy \"metal\" character, and a team of 30 \"\u2734ghting polygons.\" The single-player part of this game ends with the player's character appearing in the form of a plush doll a\u2884er depleting the 300 HP of the \"Master Hand.\" For 10 points, name this Nintendo 64 game, the \u2734rst in a series of \u2734ghters featuring characters such as Link and Mario.", "answer": "uper Smash Bros. [or Nintendo All Star! Dairanto Smash Brothers; or Nintendo Oru Suta! Dairanto Sumasshu Burazazu; accept Super Smash Bros. 64 or answers mentioning Super Smash Bros. and Nintendo 64 or N64; accept answer such as Super Smash Bros. 1 or First Super Smash Bros.]", "category": "Trash", "subcategory": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>uper Smash Bros.</u></b> [or <b><u>Nintendo All Star! Dairanto Smash Brothers</u></b>; or <b><u>Nintendo Oru Suta! Dairanto Sumasshu Burazazu</u></b>; accept <b><u>Super Smash Bros. 64</u></b> or <b><u>answers mentioning Super Smash Bros. and Nintendo 64</u></b> or <b><u>N64</u></b>; accept <b><u>answer such as Super Smash Bros. 1</u></b> or <b><u>First Super Smash Bros.</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["uper Smash Bros.", "Nintendo All Star! Dairanto Smash Brothers", "Nintendo Oru Suta! Dairanto Sumasshu Burazazu", "Super Smash Bros. 64", "answers mentioning Super Smash Bros. and Nintendo 64", "N64", "answer such as Super Smash Bros. 1", "First Super Smash Bros."], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a story from this text, a baker kills the lover of a fuller's wife by forcing him into a cage covered in sulfur-soaked clothes. During a mock trial staged in a theater, the protagonist of this text learns that three men whom he killed were actually blown-up wineskins; that episode is referenced in \"The Curious Impertinent\" from Don Quixote, which likely took its use of inset tales from this text, whose own insets include \"Tale of the Murderous Wife\" and Aristomenes's story of Socrates's heart being replaced by a sponge. Robert Graves made a 1950 translation of this text. The earliest account of the Cupid and Psyche myth is found in this text. In its eleventh and \u2734nal book, Lucius joins the cult of Isis, which allows him to become human again. For 10 points, name this Roman novel by Apuleius (a-poo-LAY-us).", "answer": "The Golden Ass [or Asinus aureus; accept The Transformations of Lucius or similar translations; accept answers mentioning Metamorphoses and Apuleius; do not accept or prompt on just \"Metamorphoses\"]", "subcategory": "Classical Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Golden Ass</u></b> [or <b><u>Asinus aureus</u></b>; accept <b><u>The Transformations of Lucius</u></b> or <b><u>similar translations</u></b>; accept <b><u>answers mentioning Metamorphoses and Apuleius</u></b>; do not accept or prompt on \"just \"Metamorphoses\"]", "acceptable": ["The Golden Ass", "Asinus aureus", "The Transformations of Lucius", "similar translations", "answers mentioning Metamorphoses and Apuleius"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": ["just \"Metamorphoses"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A 1999 book cataloguing the \"languages\" of this continent was written by Marianne Mithun. Polysynthetic words consisting of a single long cluster of obstruent consonants are characteristic of this continent's Salishan language family. Several language families on this continent use classi\u2734catory verbs, and it also contains most of the world's languages that use voiceless alveolar lateral fricatives. The most widely used alternative to the International Phonetic Alphabet was developed to describe the languages of this continent, which were divided into six families by Edward Sapir. The alleged dif\u2734culty of a language in this continent's Na-Dene family led to its use by code talkers during World War II. For 10 points, what continent's native languages include Hopi and Navajo?", "answer": "North America [accept The Languages of North America]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>North America</u></b> [accept <b><u>The Languages of North America</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["North America", "The Languages of North America"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This body of water occupies the only surviving fragment of the Dura-Europos route map, which was drawn onto the leather portion of a Roman shield. A region on this body of water was home to Alexander of Abonoteichus (ah-boh-no-\"TYKE\"-us), the prophet of a cult believing that Asclepius was reborn as the snake god Glycon. Arrian of Nicomedia wrote a periplus of this body of water, which was known as the Euxine (YOOK-seen) Sea in antiquity. Paphlagonia and Bithynia (bih-THIH-nee-ah) were regions on this sea. In Xenophon's Anabasis, this sea is greeted with the cry \"thalatta! thalatta!\" by the Ten Thousand as they approached the city of Trebizond. On the southern coast of this sea, a number of kings named Mithridates (mih-thrih-DAH-tees) ruled a region called Pontus. For 10 points, what sea borders the historical regions of Colchis and Crimea?", "answer": "Black Sea [accept Euxine Sea before \"Euxine\"; accept Black Sea a\u2884er \"sea\"; prompt on \"Black\" before \"sea\"]", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Black Sea</u></b> [accept <b><u>Euxine Sea</u></b> before \"Euxine; accept <b><u>Black Sea a\u2884er \"sea</u></b>; prompt on <u>Black\"</u> before \"sea]", "acceptable": ["Black Sea", "Euxine Sea", "Black Sea a\u2884er \"sea"], "promptable": ["Black\""], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Natty encourages the protagonist of a novel by Andrew Motion to follow in his father's footsteps by taking this document from under his father's bed. In the essay \"My First Book,\" the creator of this document wrote that it served as \"a mine of suggestion\" and generated most of the plot of the novel in which it appears. Along with a log recording various sums of gold, this document is rescued from the henchmen of the blind Pew by a boy who wraps it in an oilcloth and removes it from his father's inn. This document depicts Spyglass Hill and bears the monograph of John Flint. It launches Squire Trelawney, Jim Hawkins, and many pirates on a voyage in search of riches. For 10 points, what document from a Robert Louis Stevenson novel contains a red 'X' marking the site of buried loot?", "answer": "map of Treasure Island [or map from Treasure Island; accept Captain John Flint's map before \"Flint\"; prompt on \"map\" or \"treasure map\"; prompt on \"Captain John Flint's map\" a\u2884er \"Flint\"]", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>map of Treasure Island</u></b> [or <b><u>map from Treasure Island</u></b>; accept <b><u>Captain John Flint's map</u></b> before \"Flint; prompt on <u>map</u> or <u>treasure map</u>; prompt on <u>Captain John Flint's map\" a\u2884er \"Flint</u>]", "acceptable": ["map of Treasure Island", "map from Treasure Island", "Captain John Flint's map"], "promptable": ["map", "treasure map", "Captain John Flint's map\" a\u2884er \"Flint"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A poem criticizing this government program declares that \"the millet is scattered over the ground, the leaves of the sweet potato are withered,\" which was used as evidence to \u2734re a defense minister. A fake photo circulated by the government as part of this program appeared to show a wheat \u2734eld supporting the weight of several children. Jasper Becker highlighted foreign news coverage of this program's deadly a\u2884ermath in his book Hungry Ghosts. The effects of this program were exacerbated by the extermination of sparrows, which were labelled one of the \"Four Pests.\" As part of this program's focus on steel production, household utensils were melted down in backyard furnaces. For 10 points, what program started in 1958 and attempted to rapidly modernize the economy of China?", "answer": "Great Leap Forward [or da\u0300 yue\u0300 ji\u0300n; accept Great Leap Forward Famine; prompt on the \"Great Chinese Famine\" or \"Three Years of Dif\u2734culty\"]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Great Leap Forward</u></b> [or <b><u>da\u0300 yue\u0300 ji\u0300n</u></b>; accept <b><u>Great Leap Forward Famine</u></b>; prompt on the <u>\"Great Chinese Famine</u> or <u>Three Years of Dif\u2734culty</u>]", "acceptable": ["Great Leap Forward", "da\u0300 yue\u0300 ji\u0300n", "Great Leap Forward Famine"], "promptable": ["\"Great Chinese Famine", "Three Years of Dif\u2734culty"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This quantity and the second virial coef\u2734cient can be estimated by extrapolating a Zimm plot to \"theta equals zero.\" The Mark\u00c2\u2013Houwink (\"mark\"-OW-ink) equation sets viscosity to be a power law in this quantity. The Z-average is the third moment of this quantity's distribution. Low-angle laser light scattering, a version of DLS, measures the distribution in this quantity. In membrane osmometry (oz-MOM-eh-tree), it equals \"concentration over osmotic pressure times RT.\" The polydispersity index is the ratio of the two forms of this quantity: weight-average and number-average. Gel permeation chromatography, a type of SEC used for polymers, measures this quantity that, for biopolymers, is given in kilodaltons. For 10 points, what property, proportional to a polymer's length, is o\u2884en measured in grams per mole?", "answer": "molecular weight [or molar mass; or molecular mass; or number-average molecular weight; or weight-average molecular weight; or molecular weight distribution; prompt on M; prompt on mass; prompt on weight; prompt on size; prompt on length]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>molecular weight</u></b> [or <b><u>molar mass</u></b>; or <b><u>molecular mass</u></b>; or <b><u>number-average molecular weight</u></b>; or <b><u>weight-average molecular weight</u></b>; or <b><u>molecular weight distribution</u></b>; prompt on <u>M</u>; prompt on <u>mass</u>; prompt on <u>weight</u>; prompt on <u>size</u>; prompt on <u>length</u>]", "acceptable": ["molecular weight", "molar mass", "molecular mass", "number-average molecular weight", "weight-average molecular weight", "molecular weight distribution"], "promptable": ["M", "mass", "weight", "size", "length"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A current exhibition at the Metropolitan Museum of Art projects a \u2734lm of one of this choreographer's ballets alongside the Andrews decorative arts collection; in that ballet, this choreographer had background dancers hold the hat of a character who crawls around on all fours and mimics praying. A\u2884er commissioning a ballet with Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge, this choreographer suggested a title taken from a Hart Crane poem. This wife of dancer Erik Hawkins choreographed a ballet that ends with a married couple holding hands over a rocking chair; Merce Cunningham played a preacher in that ballet, which used sets designed by this woman's frequent collaborator Isamu Noguchi. For 10 points, what woman choreographed Aaron Copland's Appalachian Spring?", "answer": "Martha Graham", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Martha Graham</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Martha Graham"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Italo Calvino's essay on \"Lightness\" illustrates the title concept by using Ovid's account of how a hero placed this object on a bed of leaves and underwater plants to protect it from rough sands. This object contained a liquid that created the amphisbaena (am-fis-\"BYE\"-nah), an ant-eating creature that had heads on each end of its body. A man was sent to retrieve this object a\u2884er failing to supply a horse for Hippodamia's (\"hippo\"-DAH-mee-ah) wedding. This object, which was carried in a wallet called a kibisis, was used to stop Phineus from disrupting an Ethiopian princess's wedding feast. This object was mounted onto Athena's aegis (EE-jis) shield a\u2884er it was obtained using Hermes's winged sandals and a re\u2884ective shield. For 10 points, what object, severed by Perseus from the body of a Gorgon, had the power to turn people into stone?", "answer": "head of Medusa [accept answers mentioning Medusa and the idea of head or face or hair; prompt on \"body of Medusa\" or similar answers]", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>head of Medusa</u></b> [accept <b><u>answers mentioning Medusa and the idea of head</u></b> or <b><u>face</u></b> or <b><u>hair</u></b>; prompt on <u>body of Medusa</u> or <u>similar answers</u>]", "acceptable": ["head of Medusa", "answers mentioning Medusa and the idea of head", "face", "hair"], "promptable": ["body of Medusa", "similar answers"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a play by this author, a man describes how his father could walk into a barbershop and be treated like a \"big man\"; in that play by this author, Youngblood tells his girlfriend Rena that, instead of \"running around\" with her sister, he has been looking for a house with which to surprise her. A play by this man ends with Booster answering a phone with the words \"car service\" in honor of his late father, Becker, who owned a gypsy cab station. This author of Jitney wrote a play in which Gabriel cannot produce sound from his trumpet but manages to open up the heavens by dancing; in that play by this man, Cory joins the marines a\u2884er his father, a former baseball player, refuses to let him play college football. For 10 points, what playwright wrote about the garbage man Troy Maxson in his play Fences?", "answer": "August Wilson", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "August <b><u>Wilson</u></b>", "acceptable": ["August Wilson"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A group of nouveau riche merchants in Glasgow, Scotland, who primarily traded this crop were referred to as its \"lords.\" An increase in the price of this crop led a legislature to pass the Two Penny Act, which angered Anglican clergymen like James Maury who received their salaries in this crop. This crop was experimentally grown across the river from Henricus at Varina Farms. The high human capital requirements of this crop led to the implementation of the headright system. A cultivator of this crop used his newfound wealth to sail to England, where he introduced his wife as \"Rebecca.\" This crop was introduced to a colony a\u2884er the Starving Time by the man who married Pocahontas, John Rolfe. For 10 points, what crop is still cultivated in Virginia by such companies as Marlboro?", "answer": "tobacco [accept Nicotiana or Nicotiana tabacum or N. tabacum or Nicotiana rustica or N. rustica]", "subcategory": "Other History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>tobacco</u></b> [accept <b><u>Nicotiana</u></b> or <b><u>Nicotiana tabacum</u></b> or <b><u>N. tabacum</u></b> or <b><u>Nicotiana rustica</u></b> or <b><u>N. rustica</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["tobacco", "Nicotiana", "Nicotiana tabacum", "N. tabacum", "Nicotiana rustica", "N. rustica"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a play, a man with this job encourages people to memorize an anecdote about how 14 foreskins of Christ existed at the time of the Reformation; in that play, Dakin (DAY-kin) blackmails Felix Armstrong to help a man keep his job in this profession, but that man dies in an accident while riding his motorcycle with Irwin. In another play, a woman in this profession falls in love with the one-armed veteran Teddy Lloyd and is betrayed by Sandy Stranger, who gets her \u2734red by exposing her fascist sympathies; that Edinburgh resident with this job tries to shape Sandy, Monica, Jenny, Eunice, Rose, and Mary into the cre\u0300me de la cre\u0300me. Hector in Alan Bennett's The History Boys holds, for 10 points, what job also held by Muriel Spark's Jean Brodie, who works at the Marcia Blaine School for Girls?", "answer": "schoolteachers [accept answers mentioning forms of the word teach such as teaching; accept equivalents such as educators or instructors; accept speci\u2734c answers such as boys' school teachers or girls' school teachers]", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>schoolteachers</u></b> [accept <b><u>answers mentioning forms of the word teach such as teaching</u></b>; accept <b><u>equivalents such as educators</u></b> or <b><u>instructors</u></b>; accept <b><u>speci\u2734c answers such as boys' school teachers</u></b> or <b><u>girls' school teachers</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["schoolteachers", "answers mentioning forms of the word teach such as teaching", "equivalents such as educators", "instructors", "speci\u2734c answers such as boys' school teachers", "girls' school teachers"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}